HELEN (HYE Y.) KIM

662 Capp Street, #1, San Francisco, CA 94110-2691 http://fusion.sims.berkeley.edu/helki/

http://fusion.sims.berkeley.edu/helki/ helki@sims.berkeley.edu

PROFILE:

415-595-6178

Information architecture professional with over 9 years of experience working with Internet technologies. Strong background and skills in usability, needs assessment, prototyping, user interface design, and development. Master's candidate in Information Management with a concentration in Human-Computer Interaction. Seeking positions in Information Architecture, User Experience and/or Interaction Design.

EDUCATION:

University of California at Berkeley, Berkeley, CA

May 2006 (expected)

- Master of Information Management & Systems
- Selected Coursework: Needs & Usability Assessment, User Interface Design & Development, Information Organization & Retrieval, XML & Related Technologies

Barnard College, Columbia University, New York, NY

May 1995

- Bachelor of Arts in Anthropology (minor in Biology)
- *Thesis:* "How Canadian Multicultural Policy Has Affected Ethnic Identity" (research included conducting ethnographic interviews)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Database Usability Consultant, <u>Institute of International Studies</u>, UC Berkeley

Jan 2006-present

- Design and conduct user interviews and testing to pinpoint user problems with database interface.
- Analyze findings, make design recommendations, and implement redesign.
- Find and fix bugs in the PHP and mySQL code for final deployment of application.

Mobile Shopper Mobile Prototype Workshop

January 2006

- Worked with a small team of developers to design and implement a shopping application for the mobile phone using Python for Symbian OS and PHP for a week-long workshop.
- Presented prototype to peers and Yahoo! Research team.

Graduate Student Instructor, School of Information Management, UC Berkeley Sept-Dec 2005

- Prepared and led discussion sessions on various technical, social and economic topics dealing with search engine technologies. [course info]
- Gave advice and graded assignments and projects for a class of around 100 students.

HCI Researcher, SAP Research, Palo Alto, CA

Jun-Aug 2005

- Conducted and produced a literature survey that investigated methods of mapping content to user and device-specific interfaces for the <u>proactive user interface</u> project.
- Built a prototype to illustrate content mapping based on user profiles, pipelines and XSLT.
- Identified a model-based mapping framework and presented findings to peers and other departments.

Webmaster, Center for Social Services Research, UC Berkeley

Jul 2001-May 2005

- Restructured the CSSR website [homepage] to improve consistency, logic, and usability based on information architecture principles.
- Completely rebuilt a small static HTML website into a large, complex, dynamic website with ASP server-side programming.
- Originated a file-naming convention to organize and access data logically and consistently.
- Established an extensive QA tracking system working with QA team to catch errors.
- Added a searchable publications database with computer/PDA-accessible PDF downloads.
- Using SAS-generated XML, generated printer-friendly/web-friendly pages using XSL.
- Optimized search engine rankings with registration, meta-tags, and link-trades with related websites. Analyzed server logs.
- Hired, trained, managed assistants to help update the website. Created training documentation.

HELEN (HYE Y.) KIM

662 Capp Street, #1, San Francisco, CA 94110-2691 http://fusion.sims.berkeley.edu/helki/

Web Developer, Terra Lycos, Inc., San Francisco, CA

Apr 2000-May 2001

helki@sims.berkelev.edu

- Successfully delivered multiple "Artist Special Feature" pages for Lycos Music's largest client, (1M+ page views per feature). These top priority projects were highly time-sensitive and promoted throughout the network. [Lycos Music] [Hotbot]
- Hand-coded web pages using DHTML and ASP (in VBScript) according to design specifications.
- Worked with Product Managers, Designers, and QA to ensure timeliness and quality of projects.

Webmaster/ Communications Associate, International Center in NY, New York, NY Jan 1997-Feb 2000

- Supervised development, redesigned layout, edited, formatted, promoted new website [homepage] and newsletter to recruit potential volunteers and international students.
- Conducted monthly internet and e-mail workshops for members and volunteers.
- Devised complex SQL queries, reports using dbase IV, Access databases for targeted mailings.

Marketing Assistant / Tracking Coordinator, Jumbo.com, New York, NY

Sept-Dec 1996

- Tracked cost-per-1000-impressions (CPM) for online ads to ensure contractual compliance.
- Developed documentation & trained co-workers on ad-serving NetGravity software.

SCHOOL PROJECTS:

415-595-6178

Participated in needs assessment, requirements gathering, user interviews, design, development, prototyping, implementation and/or documentation in a number of class projects.

Social Responsibility Barcode Project [final project documentation]

Fall 2005-present

Consumer application that scans product ID to return social and environmental manufacturing data. Proof-of-concept prototype developed for Flash lite plug-in and Symbian OS on the mobile phone.

UFOVis [project website]

Fall 2005

Visualization of UFO sighting data incorporating the Yahoo! Maps API.

Collaborative Bargains Database Application

Fall 2005

Shopping deals aggregator and search application developed using PHP and mySQL database.

SIMster Peer-to-Peer Network Application

Spring 2005

Distributed computing application that searches for, connects, and exchanges data with peer nodes on the network.

FilterFeeder prototype application

Spring 2005

RSS feeds application that filters out/for subject keywords developed with smallx pipeline technology and XSL.

Mobile Phone Art Tour Application [project website]

Fall 2004

Faceted metadata classification framework for a mobile public art tour application using Protégé ontology editor.

SKILLS:

Software: Dreamweaver, FrontPage, EditPlus; Visual InterDev, Eclipse, Perforce, NetBeans, Smallx Pipeline Technology, Ant; ImageReady, Photoshop, Media Cleaner Pro, Real Video plug-in technology, Macromedia Flash 8, Flash Lite, Aldus PageMaker (Mac and PC), Visio; SPSS, Access, Dbase IV, ACT, MySQL and Oracle databases; WS-FTP, Cross-browser compatibilities.

Programming Languages: ASP (in VBScript), PHP, Python (Symbian OS), Java (working knowledge), JavaScript, CSS, DHTML, AJAX, HTML (hand-coder), XML, XSL, and SQL.

Other: Korean, French. Excellent written and verbal communication skills. Demonstrated team player. Thrives in collaborative environments.